

Estates and Facilities Manager
One Month
East London

A dynamic and results-focused Estates and Facilities Management professional with 10 years' experience leading hard and soft FM operations across diverse, high-profile sites in the education and private sectors. Trusted to build strong relationships with multiple stakeholders, contractors, and external clients, and to lead capital projects aligned with organisational objectives. Excels in fast-paced, compliance-driven environments and is motivated by continuous improvement, team development, and high service delivery standards.

Skills and Attributes

- Technical FM Expert PPM, reactive maintenance, and compliance across multi-building portfolios.
- Certified Health & Safety Lead NEBOSH qualified.
- · Health & Safety Compliance expertise in leading audits, risk assessments and statutory inspections.
- People Management Recruit, develop, and lead Estates and Facilities Management Teams, fostering highperformance to achieve individual and company KPIs.
- Client & Stakeholder Engagement Build and maintain robust relationships with internal and external stakeholders to Executive level.
- Budget & Financial Management Proven ability to manage multi-site budgets and deliver cost-effective solutions in excess of £1.4m.
- · CAFM Specialist Experienced in implementing CAFM platforms to track KPIs, operations, and compliance.
- · Project & Contract Management Negotiate supplier contracts, agree SLAs and manage high-value capital projects.
- Regulatory Knowledge Strong grasp of mechanical & electrical maintenance requirements, keeping abreast of statutory FM regulations.

Experience

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

Facilities Manager / London based Secondary Academy

Facilities Manager responsible for the day-to-day multi-building facilities operation and health and safety management, department lead and member of the Business Support Management Team.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Leadership and operational management of the Premises Team (4 fte staff).
- Support the Senior Leadership Team, primarily the School Business Manager and Vice Principal Business & Community in BAU school operations.
- Management of multiple service level agreements to exacting standards including cleaning, security, school lettings providers, gardeners and FM services.
- Plan, set and report on Estates and Premises KPIs.
- Build effective relationships within teams to provide a courteous, friendly service to all stakeholders both internal and external.
- Manage the Helpdesk function and ensure tasks are allocated and completed within set timeframes.
- Plan, schedule and ensure all plant and equipment is operational and maintained in a safe working condition through a specified programme of regular inspection and planned maintenance and that critical issues are identified and resolved promptly across a number of challenging and varying buildings.
- Monitor the provision of heating, lighting, water, drainage and other services and ensure teams reacting promptly to failures or hazards.





Estates and Facilities Manager
One Month
East London

- Develop a department process improvement by implementing software-based audit and compliance documentation to reduce paperwork and ensure continuity of standards.
- Plan, maintain and manage Academy transport requirements including leased vehicles.
- Digitise and store historic compliance documentation ensuring timely and thorough recordkeeping.
- Leading procurement processes on improvement, refurbishments and remedial works.
- Procurement and Stock Management using purchasing systems to adhere to procurement process and policies.
- Work closely with the Trust Estate Department and project management of capital projects.
- Project manage large, high value capital projects, actively working alongside multiple stakeholders (£1.4m in 23/24)
- Effective management of contractors and suppliers ensuring due diligence is undertaken; specifically abiding by Safeguarding procedures.
- Actively manage Academy FFE inventory, upgrading where required.
- Provide information and guidance as the schools certified Health & Safety Lead; track, and ensure compliance with Health and Safety policies and regulations across the whole School estate.
- Implement and manage the school Risk Register; review and take ownership of risk assessments ensuring all relevant hazards and working procedures are assessed and communicated to staff.
- Develop and deliver training on key Health & Safety and role specific topics.

MARCH 2022 - JANUARY 2023

Facilities Manager / London based Services business.

Facilities Manager responsible for the day-to-day multi-site facilities operation and health and safety management of a highly successful Startup.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Professional leadership and operational management of the Facilities Management function.
- Responsibility for Hard and Soft Maintenance services.
- A committee member of the Business Support Middle Managers Team.
- Review and reallocation of premises budget accounting allocation
- Responsibility of management plans across the estate for foreseeable risks including Asbestos and Legionella.
- Accountability for premises and grounds, ensuring they are maintained in accordance with agreed programmes of planned maintenance, and that emergency repairs are identified and resolved promptly.
- Management and improvement of underperforming providers bringing suppliers in line with SLA's and KPI's.
- Ensure all plant and equipment is operational and maintained in a safe working condition through a specified programme of regular inspection and planned maintenance.
- Building tender requirement and processes for future outsourced Facilities Management providers.
- Carry out repairs to furniture, equipment and the fabric of the building.
- Monitor the provision of heating, lighting, water, drainage and other services and reacting promptly to failures
 or hazards.
- Review, improve and implement waste management and sustainability strategies to reduce company expenditure and environmental impact.
- Ensure all purchasing is cost-effective and compliant with company financial systems and procedures.
- Management and assessment of contractors and suppliers.
- Build effective relationships and provide a courteous, friendly service to all stakeholders both internal and external.





Estates and Facilities Manager
One Month
East London

- Ownership of risk management ensuring all relevant hazards and working procedures are communicated to staff for safe working practices.
- Conduct monthly reviews and spot checks of Health & Safety.
- Provide and arrange training on key Health & Safety topics.
- Providing detailed reports to senior management team on facilities and estates.
- Respond to and implement recommendations from reports i.e. Fire Risk Assessments and CLEAPPS.
- Monitor the compliance of building and maintenance contractors on site, to ensure that it is in accordance with health and safety regulations.

2015 - 2022

Estates Team Leader / Large Secondary School, London, U.K.

Estates Team leader managing the day-to-day facilities operations with oversight of health and safety management.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Leadership and operational management of the Site Team and Site Security.
- Oversight of refurbishment projects from concept to completion.
- Timetabling and tracking of Hard and Soft Maintenance services.
- Procurement and Stock Management using purchasing systems to adhere to School finance policies.
- Accountability for premises and grounds kept maintained in accordance with agreed programmes of planned maintenance, and that emergency repairs are identified and actioned promptly.
- Ensure all plant and equipment is operational and maintained in a safe working condition through a specified programme of regular inspection and planned maintenance.
- Carry out repairs to furniture, equipment and the fabric of the building.
- Monitor the provision of heating, lighting, water, drainage and other services and reacting promptly to failures
 or hazards.
- Ensure all purchasing is cost-effective and made within the systems and procedures.
- Management of contractors and suppliers.
- Build effective relationships and provide a courteous, friendly service to all stakeholders both internal and external e.g. pupils, parents, staff, contractors, Estates Department and Governors.
- Manage and implement Health and Safety policies and regulations across the whole School estate.
- Writing and ownership of risk assessments ensuring all relevant hazards and working procedures and communicate to staff safe working practices.
- Conduct monthly reviews and spot checks of Health & Safety categories i.e. manual handling.
- Provide and arrange training on key Health & Safety topics
- Maintain the Health & Safety Action Plan.
- Respond to and implement recommendations from reports i.e. Fire Risk Assessments and CLEAPPS.
- Monitor the compliance of building and maintenance contractors on site, to ensure that it is in accordance with health and safety regulations.
- Carry out procedures in the event of fire, flood, breaking and entering, accident or major damage in accordance with school policy, ensuring that any event is logged and reported.
- Attend, minute and prepare reports as required for the school Health and Safety Committee.





Estates and Facilities Manager One Month East London

Education, Training & Awards

2017

NEBOSH National General Certificate in Occupational Safety & Health

British Safety Council, UK

2016

IOSH Managing Safely

British Safety Council, UK

